Estelle Ishigo papers, 1941-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Ishigo papers., 1941-1957.; 8.5 linear ft.
  - Documents, Records and Other Materials., (.5 linear ft.)
    - Photographs and snapshots taken at the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., 1942-1945.; (57 pieces) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Japanese American girl standing on steps., Date Created: January 1943.; Item no. 41; (1 photograph: black and white; 9 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Four Japanese American children., Date Created: February 1943.; Item no. 43; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 9 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Japanese American girl., Date Created: February 1943.; Item no. 44; (1 photograph: black and white; 10 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Group portrait with Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 45; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 9 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Group photo.
      - Bird's eye view of quarters and baggage at Salinas, California, Assembly Center., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 46; (1 photograph: black and white; 21 x 26 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Mountain landscape., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 47; (1 photograph: black and white; 17 x 15 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Pomona Center News staff portrait., Date Created: 1942.; Item no. 48; (1 photograph: black and white; 21 x 26 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Group portrait with Estelle Ishigo. Handwritten on recto: "Pomona 1942".
      - Loading up the truck., Date Created: 1942.; Item no. 49; (1 photograph: black and white; 13 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a drawing by Estelle Ishigo. A caption at the bottom of the drawing reads: "7 A.M. May 10, 1942."
        The drawing depicts Japanese Americans loading a truck with suitcases, preparing to move.
      - Evacuee camp., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 50; (1 photograph: black and white; 6 x 11 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of an evacuee camp with people in the background.
      - Japanese American boy with cat., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 51; (1 photograph: black and white; 18 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Oh my beloved!., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 52; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Draft of a poem about a boy named Shigeharu.
      - Scrapbook page., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 53; (1 p.; 23 x 31 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Item is a red piece of construction paper with four adhered black and white photographs.
      - Scrapbook page., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 54; (2 p.; 31 x 23 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Item is a green piece of construction paper with two adhered black and white photographs on the recto and a handwritten bar graph on the verso.
    - Correspondence relating to Estelle Ishigo's life in Federal Public Housing Authority resettlement trailer camps at Burbank, Lomita, and Harbor City, California., 1945-1948.; (36 items) (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Documents and records re the resettlement trailer camps., November 1945-June 1948. (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Incidental papers and records relating to her life in the trailer camps., 1945-1948.; (20 items) (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Snapshots taken at the trailer camps., 1945 1948.; (33 pieces) (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous personal correspondence of Estelle Ishigo., 1949-1956.; (9 items) (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Handwritten drafts of Estelle's letters, ca. 1945-ca. 1949.., (Approximately 40 items) (Box 78, Folder 12)
      - Notes: [First line begins with Thurs. June 27. moved to Cal Sea Food Tr. Camp]., 7812001-7812006; (Fair. Pencil on brown paper. Folded and torn edges.); 7812003-004 missing piece that obscures.
      - Draft letter [First line begins with To date we are still here...]., n.d.; 7812007-7812010; (Fair. Paper fading. Crinkled and torn at edges. Corners faded, as well as text.); (2 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of an unaddressed letter. Estelle writes about waiting to be moved to a new trailer camp in Burbank. She expresses worry over finding a job and affording a place to live.
        Rectos contain the main text of the letter. Versos contain brief notes.
      - Draft letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mr. Eaton [Letter: First line begins with Dear Mr. Eaton, I am finally getting ajusted (sic)...]., undated.; 7812011-7812012; (Good. Black ink with pencil corrections. Folded and also a bit crinkled.; (2 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter describing Estelle Ishigo's impressions of Los Angeles. Estelle also mentions photographs taken at Heart Mountain for a project documenting the arts there.
      - Draft letter, 1945 December 9, to Mr. Eaton [Letter: First line begins with Dear Mr. Eaton, We are in a trailer...]., Date Created: December 9, 1945.; 7812013-7812018; (Fair. Black ink. Crinkled and folded. Paper discoloring. Corrections in pencil. 7812016 in pencil.; (1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter written to Mr. Eaton describing living conditions in a temporary shelter. Estelle expresses concern over her and her husband's finances and the small size of their living quarters.
      - Draft letter, 1945 December 20, to Mr. Eaton., Date Created: December 20, 1945.; (1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter written by Estelle Ishigo to Mr. Eaton asking him if she could send some of her paintings to him for storage. It appears she was worried about them being damaged or destroyed while living in temporary housing.
      - Draft of letters written to Mr. Eaton and Edo., (3 p.: 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Item appears to be a handwritten draft of two separate letters. One is written to Mr. Eaton, the other to Estelle's friend Edo. Estelle writes of living conditions in temporary housing and small and crowded living quarters. A rough sketch of camp trailers is drawn on the first page.
      - [Note: First line begins with It looks like We are supposed to be on our own...]., 7812019-7812022; (Good. Pencil on brown paper. A bit torn on edges.)
      - [Note: First line begins with It seems our notice of intent to vacate...]., 7812023-7812024; (Fair. Pencil. Discolored paper. Torn at edges.)
      - Draft letter, 1947 April 14, Lomita, Calif. to Mr. Hanchett [Note: First line begins with Dear Mr. Hanchett, The residents of our camp...]., Date Created: April 14, 1947.; 7812025; (Good. Black ink. Paper discolored. Folded.); (1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter thanking Mr. Hanchett for a donation of clothes to the camp.
      - Draft letter, 1946 April 15, Winona, Calif. to Mrs. Courtois [Note: First line begins with Dear Mrs. Courtois (sic), Packs of little boys are playing...]., Date Created: April 15, 1946.; 7812026-7812028; (3 p.; 27 x 18 cm.); (Good. Black ink with corrections in black ink. Folded.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter describing Estelle's frustration with stressful living conditions in temporary housing.
      - Draft letter, 1946 November 11, Lomita, Calif. to Mr. Mechau [Note: First line begins with Dear Mr. Mechan, The paintings are being exhibited.]., Date Created: November 11, 1946.; 7812029-7812030; (1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.); (Good. Black ink. Folded. Paper discoloring near heading of note.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter written by Estelle Ishigo to Mr. Mechau stating that some of her paintings are being exhibited in Long Beach, Calif.
      - Draft letter, 1946 November 12, to Mr. Eaton., Date Created: November 12, 1946.; (2 p.; 25 x 21 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter to Mr. Eaton describing living conditions in temporary housing. Estelle also writes about her paintings and preparations she is making for an exhibit.
      - Draft letter, 1946 April 27, Lomita, Calif. to Mr. Tsuchiya [First line begins with Dear Mr Tsuchiya, On visiting Mr. McKillip of the Long Beach County...]., Date Created: April 27, 1946.; 7812031-7812032; (Good. Black ink. Folded. Paper is discoloring. Pencil corrections.); (2 p.; 27 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter describing the Ishigos' frustrating attempts at receiving assistance from the Long Beach County welfare office.
      - Draft letter, 1946 May 14, to Mr. Tsuchiya [First line begins with Dear Mr. Tsuchiya, We nearly lost the trailer with all our...]., Date Created: May 14, 1946.; 7812033-7812034; (1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.); (Good. Black ink with pencil. Corrections. Brown paper.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter detailing recent experiences at their temporary shelter. Estelle complains of having to move frequently.
      - Draft letter, 1946 March 30, Lomita, Calif. to Mrs. Courtois [First line begins with Dear Mr. Courtois (sic), I tried to get in touch with you...]., Date Created: March 30, 1946.; 7812035-7812036; (Good. Black ink, some pencil notes. Folded. Paper a little discolored.); (2 p.; 27 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter detailing the Ishigos' move from a camp in Burbank to one in Lomita. Estelle expresses frustration with being repeatedly moved and detained.
      - [Note: November 13.. First line begins with Dear Mr. Mechan, It was something like the house life...]., 7812037-7812038; (Good. Black ink and pencil corrections. Folded and torn near heading (obscures heading).
      - [Note: First line begins with At present A is getting along allright (sic)...]., 7812039-7812042; (Good. Pencil. Folded and crinkled at edges. Paper discoloring.)
      - Draft letter to Tai [Note: First line begins with Dear Tai, I recieved (sic) your very...]., n.d.; 7812049-7812051; (2 p.; 21 x 13 cm.); (Good. Carbon copy? With pencil corrections. Slightly folded.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter written to Estelle's friend Tai. Mention is made of an exhibit of Estelle's paintings in New York and looking for affordable housing in California.
      - Draft letter to Tai [Note: First line begins with Dear Tai, How I wish I was in New York!]., n.d.; 7812052-7812054; (3 p.; 27 x 21 cm.); (Fair. Pencil. Hole punched. Pieces torn off at the edge near perforated holes. Paper discolored.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter written to Estelle's friend Tai. In it she complains about their current living situations and difficulty finding affordable housing.
      - Draft letter to Tai [Note: January 7.. First line begins with Dear Tai, With all the snow and blizzards...]., undated.; 7812055-7812061; (5 p.; 25 x 21 cm.); (Good. Black ink with blue scribbles on 7812055. 7812060-061 folded at corners, crinkled along edges. Paper discolored.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter written to Estelle's friend Tai in new York City. The letter is written over the course of several days. Estelle writes about painting and music, as well as Arthur's attempts to find work. Mention is also made of the Japanese American Theater Guild.
      - [Note: May 10, 1946.. First line begins with Dear Mrs. Courtois,I've just received word that...]., 7812062; (Good. Pencil with writing in black ink.
      - [Note: May 11, 1946.. First line begins with Dear Mrs. Courtois, We were in an amusing situation...]., 7812063; (Good. Black ink and pencil. Crinkled and a bit torn at edges. Folded. Paper discolored.)
      - [Note: First line begins with I enquired (sic) on Monday May 5...]., 7812064-7812065; (Good. Folded. Crinkled corners. Paper discolored.)
      - [Note: First line begins with Thanks so much for mailing dictionary...]., 7812066-7812067; (Good. Pencil. Smudged. Folded.)
      - [Note: First line begins with About notice of intent to vacate...]., 7812068; (Good. Pencil. Folded. Slightly crimped and torn on top.)
      - [Note: First line begins with MST has asked me if I could possibly...]., 7812069-7812070; (Good. Pencil. Folded. Corners are slightly crinkled and torn. Discolored papers.)
      - [Note: First line begins with I enquired (sic) at the office on Mon. May 5...]., 7812071-7812072; (Good. Pencil. Slightly torn at edges. Discolored paper.)
      - [Note: First line begins with Most of the living conditions...]., 7812073-7812074; (Good. Pencil. Folded. Slightly torn at edges. Discolored paper.)
      - [Note: First line begins with I think I know what it might be...]., 7812075-7812076; (Good. Pencil. Smudged.)
      - [Note: First line begins with Mechan I would like to ask...]., 7812077-7812080; (Fair. Pencil. Folded and torn. Discolored paper.)
      - [Note: May 8, 1946.. First line begins with I enquired (sic) at the office on Mon. May 5 about the change of...]., 7812081-7812082; (Fair. Pencil and black ink writing. Wrinkled and folded. Torn at edges. Discolored paper.)
      - [Note: First line begins with I'll probably never hear from Mr. Mechan (sic)...]., 7812083-7812085; (Good. Pencil and black ink writing. Folded and torn at the edges. Discolored along edges.)
      - [Note: First line begins with I've written Mr. M. and enclosed a copy...]., 7812086
      - Draft letter, 1948 June 1, Lomita, Calif. to Dr. Owen C. Coy, California Historical Association, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: June 1, 1948.; Item no. 41; (1 p.; 26 x 16 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter from Estelle Ishigo to the California State Historical Association stating that most of her documentation of the Heart Mountain Japanese Relocation Center would be available to researchers.
      - Draft letter, 1948 June 4, Lomita, Calif. to Richard J. Walsh, New York, N.Y., (6 p.; 26 x 16 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter written by Estelle Ishigo in which she complains about temporary housing living conditions and attempts at finding affordable housing. Also mentioned is an album of Estelle's sketches that was left at the addressee's office.
        The letter is addressed to: Richard J. Walsh, The John Day Company, 40 East 49th Street, New York City 17, N.Y.
      - Draft letter, 1948 June 1, Lomita, Calif. to the War Relocation Authority., Date Created: June 1, 1948.; (2 p.; 26 x 16 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Handwritten draft of a letter inquiring on the whereabouts of Estelle Ishigo's paintings. Includes a list of paintings.
      - Draft letter, 1948 July 2, Lomita, Calif. to Mr. Henry Mori., Date Created: July 2, 1948.; (1 p.; 26 x 20 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter from Estelle Ishigo regarding joining a local orchestra.
      - Draft letter, 1948 October 15, to Tai., Date Created: October 15, 1948.; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter to Estelle's good friend Tai telling him about being evicted from a trailer park in Los Angeles.
      - Draft letter, 1948 October 27, to Mr. Brown., Date Created: October 27, 1948.; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
        Draft of a letter describing being evicted from a trailer park in Los Angeles.
      - Draft letter to Mr. Eaton., undated.; (4 p.; 20 x 13 cm. plus 2 p.; 26 x 16 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and Documents., (.5 linear ft.)
    re the Ishigos' evacuation claims and manuscripts for Estelle Ishigo's short stories and essays.
    - Correspondence re the Ishigos' postwar evacuation claims., 1952-1954.; (32 items) (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Letter, 1952 April 4, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: April 4, 1952.; Item no. 1; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter acknowledging Estelle Ishigo's letter regarding Arthur Ishigo's claim in connection with the Japanese Evacuation Claims Act.
        Letterhead: Congress of the United States, House of Representatives, Member Committee on Ways and Means, Cecil R. King, Seventeenth District California.
      - Letter, 1952 March 30, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mr. King., Date Created: March 30, 1952.; Item no. 2; (4 p.; 26 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Handwritten copy of a letter written to Congressman Cecil R. King in regards to Arthur Ishigo's claim in connection with the Japanese Evacuation Claims Act. Estelle is protesting the fact that she has been deemed ineligible for benefits because she is not of Japanese descent.
      - Evacuation claims compromise settlement award sheet., Date Created: 1952.; Item no. 3; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm. plus 1 note; 5 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Statement of awards stating that Arthur Ishigo will be awarded $102.50 in a compromise settlement of his original claim of $1325.00. The attached note states that there will be a delay in payment due to depletion of funds.
        A copy of this letter was also sent to Mssrs. Kenny and Morris, Attorneys at Law, 250 North Hope St. Los Angeles 12, Calif.
      - Letter, 1952 January 8, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mr. Arthur Ishigo, Hawthorne, Calif., Date Created: January 8, 1952.; Item no. 4; (4 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Item consists of a three page letter written to Arthur Ishigo. Also enclosed is a copy of a one page letter dated Jan. 3, 1952, written by Mr. Ishigo's attorney and addressed to the U.S. Dept. of Justice. The subject of both letters is Mr. Ishigo's claim in connection with the Japanese Evacuation Claims Act and the Dept. of Justice's compromise offer which is substantially lower than Mr. Ishigo's original claim amount.
      - Letter, 1952 March 7, Los Angeles, Calif. to President Truman., Date Created: March 7, 1952.; Item no. 5; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Handwritten draft of a letter written to President Truman detailing problems Estelle and her husband had been having in relation to their Japanese Evacuation Claim settlement. Estelle protests the fact that she has been deemed ineligible for a claim due to not being of Japanese ancestry.
      - Letter, 1952 April 25, Washington, D.C. to Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: April 25, 1952.; Item no. 6; (3 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written in response to Estelle's correspondence regarding Mr. Ishigo's Japanese Evacuation Claims Act claim. Enclosed are two letters from the Asst. Attorney General of the U.S. Dept. of Justice also concerning the matter.
      - Letter, 1952 May 23, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: May 23, 1952.; Item no. 7; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written by the Secretary to Congressman Cecil R. King acknowledging receipt of Estelle Ishigo's letter.
      - Letter, 1952 May 14, Los Angeles, Calif. to Honorable Cecil R. King, Washington, D.C., Date Created: May 14, 1952.; Item no. 8; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter explaining Estelle's previous letters to Congressman King and President Truman. Estelle complains of the injustice inherent in Public Law 886 and the racial bias the law represents.
      - Letter, 1952 May 14, Los Angeles, Calif. to Holmes Baldridge, Washington, D.C., Date Created: May 14, 1952.; Item no. 9; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written in response to U.S. Asst. Attorney General Holmes Baldridge's letter regarding Mr. Ishigo's Japanese Evacuation Claims Act claim.
      - Letter, 1952 June 16, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: June 16, 1952.; Item no. 10; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written in response to Mrs. Ishigo's inquiry as to the introduction of appropriate legislation in response to Public Law 886.
      - Letter, 1952 June 24, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: June 24, 1952.; Item no. 11; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm. plus 1 p.; 28 x 39 cm. folded to 28 x 20 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from California Congressman Cecil R. King stating that he has introduced Bill H.R. 8342 to authorize the Attorney General to adjudicate claims of American spouses of persons of Japanese ancestry resulting from evacuation under military orders.
      - Letter, 1953 Nov. 9, Washington D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: November 9, 1953.; Item no. 12; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from the U.S. Department of Justice, Claims Division and Japanese Claims Division, regarding the evacuation claim of Mr. Ishigo. The letter addresses Mrs. Ishigo's role in the claim as a non-Japanese spouse.
      - Letter, 1953 July 28, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: July 28, 1953.; Item no. 13; (2 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from the U.S. Dept. of Justice regarding the evacuation claim of Mr. Ishigo, and their refusal of payment to spouses of non-Japanese ancestry.
      - Letter, 1953 May 27, Los Angeles, Calif. to Honorable Herbert Brownell., Date Created: May 27, 1953.; Item no. 14; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter to the U.S. Attorney General explaining Estelle's predicament in Mr. Ishigo's Japanese Evacuation claim.
      - Letter, 1953 August 20, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: August 20, 1953.; Item no. 15; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from California Congressman Cecil R. King regarding the Ishigo's Japanese Evacuation claim. Congressman King advises Mrs. Ishigo on how to proceed with her claim by attempting to prove that she had no real choice but to go to a relocation center with her husband.
      - Letter, 1953 Aug. 4, Los Angeles, Calif. to Congressman Cecil R. King, Washington, D.C., Date Created: August 4, 1953.; Item no. 16; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter regarding Estelle's claim as an evacuee for loss of property during their internment. She requests a copy of the Downs ruling and describes her case.
      - Letter, 1953 October 22, Los Angeles, Calif. to Hon. Warren E. Burger, Washington, D.C., Date Created: October 22, 1953.; Item no. 17; (4 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Estelle Ishigo's detailed account of her and her husband's evacuation and their struggles afterwards. This account is written to appeal to the U.S. Dept. of Justice's decision to not compensate Mrs. Ishigo for losses due to evacuation because she is not of Japanese descent.
      - Letter, 1954 February 15 to Hon. Sam Yorty, Washington, D.C., Date Created: February 15, 1954.; Item no. 18; (1 p.; 28 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter accompanying a fact sheet detailing the Ishigo's long struggle with government officials for recognition of their Japanese evacuation claim for compensation.
      - Letter, 1954 February 15, to Mr. Mike Masaoka, Washington, D.C., Date Created: February 15, 1954.; Item no. 19; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter accompanying a fact sheet detailing the Ishigo's long struggle with government officials for recognition of their Japanese evacuation claim.
      - Letter, 1954 February 15, Los Angeles, Calif. to Honorable Cecil R. King, Washington, D.C., Date Created: February 15, 1954.; Item no. 20; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Letter, 1953 December 21, Washington, D.C. to Mr. J. Allan Frankel, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: December 21, 1953.; Item no. 21; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written to acknowledge receipt of a letter written by J. Allan Frankel. The letter addresses the possibility of introducing legislation on behalf of Estelle Ishigo and her Japanese evacuation claim.
      - Letter, 1953 December 10, to Honorable Cecil R. King, Washington, D.C., Date Created: December 10, 1953.; Item no. 22; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)